A night that changed her life became a scandal that rocked a nation.
Black Box Diaries is a documentary film directed by Shiori Ito.
Journalist Shiori Ito embarks on a courageous investigation of her own sexual
assault in an improbable attempt to prosecute her high-profile offender.
Her quest becomes a landmark case in Japan, exposing the
country's outdated judicial and societal systems.
Self, played by Shiori Ito.
Self (archive footage), played by Noriyuki Yamaguchi.
Self (archive footage), played by Shinzo Abe.
Black Box Diaries (Japanese: ブラック・ボックス・ダイアリーズ, romanized: Burakku Bokkusu
Daiarīzu) is a 2024 documentary film directed by Shiori Itō.
The film chronicles her investigation into her own sexual assault case.
The film premiered at the 2024 Sundance Film Festival.
It was released in the United States and United Kingdom on October 25,
2024, by MTV Documentary Films and Dogwoof, respectively.
The film was named one of the top 5 documentary films of 2024 by the National Board of Review, won a
Peabody Award, and was nominated for Best Documentary Feature Film in the 97th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of japan, sexual violence,
justice, human rights, female journalist.